Ruben D. Garcia, Senior Software Engineer

Nueva Esparta, Venezuela, rubendariogp99@gmail.com, +58 (412) 356 6820, www.linkedin.com/in/rubengp99/

PROFILE

Seasoned software engineer with 5+ years of experience with Go and AWS mainly. I bring to the table strong knowledge in distributed systems, event-driven architectures, test-driven development, CI/CD and Infrastructure as Code. With strong leadership, ownership, communication skills and expertise in Fintech. In the other hand I have previous exposure to fast-paced startups, full-stack roles and multiple database managers (both SQL and NoSQL).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jun 2021 — Dec 2024

LEAD ENGINEER, Cadana (Full-Time)

Remote

- Optimized AWS usage, cutting costs by 30% through DynamoDB and architecture improvements.
- Developed and implemented a custom business testing framework standardized across microservices.
- Mentored junior engineers and ensured alignment between technical initiatives and business goals through stakeholder collaboration.
- Provided an end-to-end Web3 U.S. equity investment product, expanding the company's fintech capabilities.
- Built and launched a virtual card product with AML-focused rules, enhancing fraud prevention and customer fund security.
- Delivered an end-to-end Web3 U.S. equity investment product, expanding the company's fintech capabilities

May 2020 — Jun 2021

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, Esusu (Full-Time)

Remote

- Automated rent data ingestion from 4 real estate platforms, streamlining monthly reporting.
- Developed internal messaging platform to improve customer communications and campaigns.
- Built an MVP admin UI, reducing operations' reliance on developers.
- Hardened platform resiliency with retry flows and optimized MongoDB cluster usage.

Feb 2020 — Aug 2020

PROJECT MANAGER, Somos Sistemas (Contract)

Remote

- Managed Trello/Jira boards and configured core hosting rules, streamlining operations and ensuring product performance.
- Directed cloud migration from on-premises to cloud hosting, improving scalability, reliability, and maintenance.
- Led the team to design and implement a CRM extension of the ERP product in 2 months, enabling organization-wide business intelligence and accelerating data-driven decision-making.

EDUCATION

Jul 2015 — May 2020

Engineers' Degree in Systems Engineering, Universidad de Margarita (UNIMAR)

Nueva Esparta, Venezuela

	8	,		· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·
SKILLS	Golang		React.js	
	Node.js		Vue.js	
	AWS		TypeScript	
	MongoDB		Docker	
	Microservices		PostgreSQL	
	Python		Infrastructure as Code	
	TDD		CI/CD	
LANGUAGES	Spanish	Native speaker	English	Highly proficient